AKI GAO

xiaoyu.akihiro.gao@gmail.com | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a JavaScript developer with a passion for technology and innovation, in particular Blockchain and the Web. I offer two years of experience in full stack web application development from conception through delivery of elegant and maintainable solutions. My expertise ranges from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly web-based UX/UIs to architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures. Specifically, I specialize in web application development using the React and Node is ecosystems. My personal mission is to use technology and entreprenership to create a more compassionate and humancentric future by empowering people to connect more meaningfully and reducing socioeconomic inequality.

Education

Skills

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

• Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering

August 2016

Languages:

• JavaScript (ES5/ES6/ES7/ES8), Shell (Bash)

UX/UI and Front End Technologies and Tools:

• Sketch, HTML, CSS, JQuery, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, Redux-Thunk, React Router, Reach Router, CSS Modules, PostCSS

Blockchain Technologies:

• Ethereum, Solidity, Web3, Truffle, Ganache, Remix, Geth

Development and Testing Tools:

Agile (Scrum/Kanban), Git, NPM, Yarn, Webpack, Babel, Mocha,
Chai

Back End and Database Technologies:

• Node.js, Express, Helmet, Mongoose, MongoDB, MySQL

Infrastructure and Infrastructure Technologies:

Apache, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Travis, Terraform, Packer, AWS,
Azure, Google Cloud

Work Experience

Freelance Consulting - Javascript & Blockchain Developer

February 2018 - Present

- Provide services to clients to architect and develop front end and back end applications, as well as smart contracts.
- Also offer work to clients seeking development capabilities for planned or existing projects.
- Special focus in a JavaScript-based stack including the React and Node.js ecosystem for the front end and back end respectively, as well as Solidity for smart contract development on the Ethereum network.

Alluminate - Javascript & Blockchain Developer

October 2017 - February 2018

- Provide high-level technology expertise and development capabilities for in-house and consulting work ranging from UX/UI to smart contract development.
- Designed, developed and maintained the Alluminate homepage and the CryptoPets landing page.
- Core development member of the CryptoPets platform, an Ethereum-based game platform for collecting and battling digital pets developed in partnership with Arcade Distillery.
- Smart contracts written in Solidity implement ERC721 to tokenize in-game pet ownership.
- Aided in smart contract design, as well as audited smart contracts for correctness.
- Developed in-house development and testing environment using Web3, Docker and Geth.

Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - November 2017

- U.S. Treasury Proof of Concept Blockchain Application July 2017 August 2017
 - Developed a proof of concept Blockchain application for the U.S. Treasury to replace existing payment infrastructure.
 - Application built with a Javascript stack (React/Redux and Node.js) and deployed to Azure Cloud.
 - Smart contracts written in Solidity with Truffle and deployed to Microsoft's Blockchain network.
 - Architected the front end, back end and deployment pipeline, as well as the cloud infrastructure for the project.
 - Led development efforts across the stack, including the UX/UI design, front end, back end and devops, in a small team of developers in an Agile environment using Kanban.
 - Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and to convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.
 - Participation, expertise and leadership in project led to converting the project from a Proof of Concept work into a full-fledged proposal for a bid for a contract.
- FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment September 2017 November 2017
 - Architected and bootstrapped the front end for the FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment Project.
 - Front end logic built with React, Redux, React Router, Redux Form, and user interface styled with custom CSS using CSS modules and PostCSS.
 - Led front end development efforts, including designing the UX/UI, implementing application logic, and providing high level guidance to other developers.